desitwist.com 2010-01-06

# Desi Forums - Privacy Policy

**About DesiTwist.com**  
DesiTwist.com is an online service that allows our members to set up unique personal profiles. DesiTwist.com members can view including, but not limited to each others' profiles, communicate with old friends and meet new friends on the service, share photos, and describe their interests. To enrich our members' experience, we request and display some personal information to other members and visitors, which allows our users to identify each other and expand their network of friends. DesiTwist.com members can change their profile information at any time and can control how other members and the service communicates with them. 

**Information Collection and Use by DesiTwist.com**  
DesiTwist.com collects user submitted information such as name, email address, and age to authenticate users and to send notifications to those users relating to the DesiTwist.com service. DesiTwist.com also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, location, and occupation in order to assist users in finding and communicating with each other. 

DesiTwist.com also logs non-personally-identifiable information including IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, and browser type, from users and visitors to the site This data is used to manage the website, track usage and improve the website services. This non-personally-identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to members. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes 

User Profile information including members' pictures and first names are displayed to people in order to facilitate user interaction in the DesiTwist.com desi social networking community. Email addresses are used for the purposes of sending notifications related to the service.

We may also use a user's email address to send updates, a newsletter or news regarding the service.

**Use of Cookies**  
DesiTwist.com uses cookies to store visitors' preferences and to record session information, for purposes including ensuring that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and user profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set -- each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences -- however, you must enable cookies from DesiTwist.com in order to use most functions on the site Please note that DesiTwist.com allows 3rd party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the DesiTwist.com Privacy Policy. 

**Links** ****  
DesiTwist.com contains links to sites. DesiTwist.com is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on DesiTwist.com.

**Chat Rooms, WebLogs, Message Boards, Private Messages and Public Forums**  
Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to WebLogs, Message Boards, Private Messages or any other Public Forums that that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications. 

**Correcting/Updating or Removing Information**  
DesiTwist.com users may modify or remove any of their personal information at any time by logging into their account and accessing features such as Edit Profile.

**Email Choice/Opt-out**  
Members who no longer wish to receive updates or notifications may choose not to by updating their user profile.

**Accont Deletion**  
We do not delete member accounts based on their request(s). If you do not wish to be a part of DesiTwist.com then please do not register yourself. All the information provided by members are kept confidential as described in this newsletter. 

**Third Party Advertising**  
Ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by DesiTwist.com or one of our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by DesiTwist.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

**Security**  
DesiTwist.com member accounts are secured by member-created passwords DesiTwist.com takes precautions to insure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our co-administrators. Member's password is encrypted & it is not available to anyone other than the member. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time For any additional information about the security measures we use on DesiTwist.com, please contact us a <http://www.desitwist.com/sendmessage.php>

**Sharing and Disclosure of Information DesiTwist.com Collects**  
Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, DesiTwist will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by DesiTwist.com, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the DesiTwist.com Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service. DesiTwist.com reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of DesiTwist.com or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest For more information see the "Changes in Our Privacy Policy" section below. 

**Changes in Our Privacy Policy**  
From time to time we may make changes to our privacy policy If we make changes, we will post them on our site to make users aware of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. A User is bound by any minor changes to the policy when she or he uses the site after those changes have been posted If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days. 

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at: <http://www.desitwist.com/sendmessage.php>
